American Association of Retired Persons, Schenectady County Chapter, #490 apap181
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
American Association of Retired Persons, Schenectady County Chapter, #490
1967-2003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
American Association of Retired Persons. Schenectady County Chapter 490
apap181
2.5 cubic ft.
This collection contains the American Association of Retired Persons, Schenectady County Chapter, #490's official newsletters, treasurer's reports, correspondence, various national and local publications, newspaper clippings, certificates, and the chapter banner.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Ronald Alheim donated the records to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in 2004.
Historical Note
The American Association for Retired Persons (AARP), Schenectady County Chapter #490, was established on April 4, 1968 and disbanded in 2004. The chapter published a newsletter, The Reporter, to update and inform members of upcoming events and New York legislation. One particularly active member of this chapter was Helen Quirini, whose collection of papers is also held at this repository and who served as chapter president. Most presidents and other members of the executive board held those positions for a two-year term.
Scope and Contents
The AARP Schenectady County Chapter, #490 held monthly executive board meetings, and monthly general membership meetings. This is reflected in the records. The Schenectady County Chapter encouraged members to write to government representitvies voicing their opinion on health care, as well as donating to local charities and attending events at Proctors in Schenectady. The chapter also published a bimonthly newsletter, The Reporter, to keep members up-to-date on chapter activites and advertise the chapter's outings. Throughout the collection is material on Medicare and access to prescription drugs.
The archivist preserved the original order of this collection. However, multiple members of this chapter compiled the collection of materials throughtout the chapter's lifetime and the influence of multiple records creators/keepers is evident. While the collection is in chronological order, the year spans are in multiple folders and duplicate materials may be found in mulitple folders. Files titled, "meeting minutes" may also include The Reporter, treasureer's reports, newspaper clippings, list of members, AARP national publications, and other community publications.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized chronologically. There are no series.
Medicare; Retirees--New York (State); Newsletters; Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence; American Association of Retired Persons. Schenectady County Chapter 490
- Meeting minutes, correspondence, and treasurer's reports, 1967; 1985-1986; Undated (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 1)
- Meeting minutes, meeting agendas, and correspondence (1 of 2), 1967-1977 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 2)
- Meeting minutes, meeting agendas, and correspondence (2 of 2), 1967-1977 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 3)
- Certificates of incorporation, and adapting AARP Chapter bylaws, 1968; 1978 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 4)
- Meeting minutes, list of members and positions, and The Reporter, 1969; 1972-1975; Undated (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 5)
- Meeting minutes, correspondence, and The Reporter, 1969; 1972-1975; Undated (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 6)
- Board of Director meeting minutes, and The Reporter, 1969-1976 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 7)
- Executive Board and general meeting minutes, 1972-1978 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 8)
- The Reporter, and correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 9)
- Meeting minutes, The Reporter, and correspondence, 1973 January - 1976 June (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 10)
- Meeting minutes, correspondence, and treasurer's reports, 1973-1976 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 11)
- List of Executive Board members and meeting minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 12)
- Meeting minutes, The Reporter, and correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 13)
- Executive Board meeting minutes, and budget reports, 1976-1978 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 14)
- Meeting minutes, treasurer's reports, and correspondence (1 of 2), 1976-1983 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 15)
- Meeting minutes, treasurer's reports, and correspondence (2 of 2), 1976-1983 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Board member training materials, and The Reporter, 1977; 1979-1981; Undated (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 17)
- Board of Director meeting minutes, treasurer's reports, and The Reporter, 1978-1983; 1987-1989 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 18)
- The Reporter, budget reports, correspondence, and newspaper clippings, 1979-1981 (Box 1 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Executive Board training material, and The Reporter (1 of 2), 1979-1983 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 1)
- Correspondence, Executive Board training material, and The Reporter (2 of 2), 1979-1983 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 2)
- Meeting minutes, meeting agendas, and treasurer's reports, 1980-1983; 1987-1989; Undated (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 3)
- Mohawk Senior Citizens Leadership Council correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 4)
- Meeting minutes, pamphlets, correspondence, and treasurer's reports, 1983-1984; 1988-1989; 1990 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 5)
- Certificates, 1983; 1986 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 6)
- Executive Board and general meeting minutes, and correspondence, 1983; 1987; Undated (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 7)
- Meeting minutes, correspondence, The Reporter, and treasurer's reports (1 of 2), 1983-1985 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 8)
- Meeting minutes, correspondence, The Reporter, and treasurer's reports (1 of 2), 1983-1985 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 9)
- Pamphlets, and event flyers, 1984; Undated (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 10)
- Treasurer's reports, 1984-1989 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 11)
- Executive Board and general meeting minutes, and correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 12)
- Meeting minutes, treasurer's reports, and newspaper clippings (1 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 13)
- Meeting minutes, treasurer's reports, and newspaper clippings (2 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 14)
- Executive Board meeting reports, correspondence, and treasurer's reports, 1985-1989 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 15)
- Executive Board and general membership meeting minutes, 1986; Undated (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 16)
- Meeting minutes and meeting agendas, 1986-1990 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 17)
- Chapter bylaws, and standing rules, 1987; Undated (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 18)
- Executive Board and general meeting minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 19)
- Treasurer's reports, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 20)
- Executive Board and general meeting minutes, 1988-1989 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 21)
- Budget, 1989; Undated (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 22)
- Executive Board and general meeting minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 23)
- Executive Board and general meeting minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 24)
- Membership list and Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 25)
- Meeting minutes, budget reports, correspondence, and The Reporter, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 1)
- Resolution and awards, 1992-1993; 2003 (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 2)
- Chapter handbook, and AARP national publications, 1993; Undated (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 3)
- The Reporter, 1993-1995 (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 4)
- Correspondence, meeting minutes, and The Reporter (1 of 2), 1995-1998; Undated (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 5)
- Correspondence, meeting minutes, and The Reporter (2 of 2), 1995-1998; Undated (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 6)
- AARP national pamphlets, and promotional materials, 1996; Undated (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 7)
- Correspondence, AARP national publications, and New York State publications, (1 of 2), 1996-1997 (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 8)
- Correspondence, AARP national publications, and New York State publications, (1 of 2), 1996-1997 (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 9)
- Chapter banner, Undated (Map-file 1)
- Chapter certificate, Undated (Flat-file 1)
- Standing rules, and by-laws, Undated (Box 3 (American Association of Retired Persons, Schenecta), Folder 10)